Register of the Stanley Kuhl Hornbeck papers, 1900-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject and Correspondence File, 1842-1966 (Boxes 1-452)
  - Liberation Day, Netherlands, May 4
  - "Liberation" Conference, 1953 December
  - The Liberator
  - Liberty
  - Library of Congress
  - Lichtenstein, Walter
  - van Lidth de Jeude, O. C. A.
  - Liebman, Marvin
  - Lieftinck, P.
  - Lieu, D. K., letter to
  - Lieu, D. K.
  - Lieu, D. K., Communist China, economic
  - Life Magazine
  - Lightner, M. C.
  - Lilienthal, David
  - Lin Sen
  - Lin Yutang, Chinese
  - Lincoln, Abraham
  - Lincoln, Abraham, poetry of
  - Lincoln, Edmond E.
  - Lindbergh, Charles A. (Box 279)
  - van der Linden, P. W. J. H. Cort
  - Lindley, Ernest K.
  - Linebarger, Judge Paul Myron
  - Linebarger, Paul M., "Scientific Method and Australian Foreign Policy"
  - Linguaphone Institute
  - Linley, Richard
  - Linneman, Francis P.
  - J. B. Lippincott Co.
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - Lippmann, Walter, Press clippings, 1934-1945
  - Lipschutz, Isidore
  - Literary Digest (Box 280)
  - Literary Society
  - Literature
  - Littell, John S.
  - Littell, Norman
  - Little, Lester K.
  - Little, Lester K. and Knox, Robert and Cosmos Club, 1954
  - Litvinnof, Maxim
  - Liu Chieh
  - Liu, James T. C.
  - Lloyd, Wildon
  - Lloyd-Jones, (Mrs.) Chester
  - Loans
  - Lobenstine, Edwin C.
  - Lochner, Dr. Louis P.
  - Lockhart, C. C.
  - Lockhart, Frank P.
  - Lockwood, William W.
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot
  - Loeb, William, Jr.
  - Loftus, Edward H.
  - Loftus, Roderick E.
  - Logan Act
  - Logan, Lt. Arthur B.
  - Logic, outline
  - London
  - London, S. K. Hornbeck to, 1943 October
  - London, Declaration of
  - London, Declaration of, A Digest
  - London Naval Conference and Treaty
  - London North Eastern Railway
  - London Times
  - Long, Rear Admiral Andrew T.
  - Long Beach Conference, 1917
  - Long, Breckinridge
  - Loomis, Charles F.
  - Loomis, Helen M.
  - van Loon, Henry (Box 281)
  - Loose, Mrs. Jacob Leander
  - Loshan-Sichang Highway
  - Lothian, Lord (British ambassador)
  - Loudon, Alexander
  - Loveman, Amy
  - Lovinck, A. H. J.
  - Lowe, James T.
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence
  - Lowell lectures
  - Lowrie, S. Gale
  - Lowry, Reverend Charles W.
  - Loyalties
  - Lucas, Capt. A. H. S.
  - Luccock, E. W.
  - Luce, Henry R. and Clare B., 2.0 folders)
  - Ludlow Resolution
  - Ludwig, Albert P.
  - Luncheon Club (Academic Group)
  - Luncheon Club (Monday Club, Far East Group)
  - Lundeen, Ernest
  - Lunt, Carroll
  - Lunt, William E.
  - Lusitania case, history
  - Luther, Jack A.
  - Lutz, Ralph H.
  - Lux, Rev. J. S.
  - Luxembourg Grand Duchy, 1905
  - Lybyer, Albert Howe
  - Lyford, Mrs. Oliver
  - Lynch, Andrew G.
  - Lynch, Mrs. F. B.
  - Lynden, Colonel
  - Lynden, J. C. E. Bn.
  - Lyon, Cecil B.
  - Lyon, Sarah S.
  - Lyons, Eugene
  - Lyttelton, Oliver
  - Lytton, Lord
  - Maas, Melvin J. (Box 282)
  - van Maasdijk, I. G.
  - Maastricht (visit to)
  - Macao
  - MacArthur, General Douglas, U.S.A., Chief of Staff
  - McBride, Harry A.
  - McCarthy on Marshall
  - McCarthy on McCarthyism
  - McCartney, Albert Joseph
  - McClatchy, V. S.
  - McClellan, George B.
  - McClintock, Robert Mills
  - McClure, Wallace
  - McConaughy, Walter, 1955
  - McCord, (Mrs.) Joseph Alexander
  - McCormick, Frederick
  - McCormick, J. Robinson
  - McCoy, General Frank R.
  - McCracken, John H.
  - McDermott, Michael J.
  - MacDonald, Anne
  - MacDonald, Charles A.
  - McDonald, Donald
  - McDonald, James G., Foreign Policy Association (Box 283)
  - McDonough, R. P.
  - McDowell, Arthur G., general
  - McDowell, Arthur G., 1951-1957
  - McDowell, William F. (bishop)
  - McEntee, Colonel G. L.
  - McGinnis, J. Paul
  - McGovern, William Montgomery
  - McGraw, James H., Jr.
  - McHugh, James M.
  - McIvor letter
  - Mackay, Raymond
  - McKee, Oliver
  - McKenna, James E.
  - McKinney, Alexis
  - McKittrick, H. V.
  - McKnight, Edna Clarinda
  - McLaren, Walter W.
  - McLean, J. S.
  - MacMillan Company
  - McMullen, Rev. Robert Johnston
  - MacMurray, John V. A. (Box 284)
  - MacNair, Harley Farnsworth (Box 285)
  - MacNair, H. F., American Far Eastern Policy
  - McNamee, Admiral Luke
  - McNerney, Gerald F.
  - McNiece, Irwin
  - McNutt, Paul V.
  - McPhail, Mrs.
  - McPherson, O. H. M.
  - McVay, Rear Admiral Charles B., Jr.
  - MacVeagh, Mrs. Charles
  - Madagascar
  - Madariaga (Salvador de)
  - Magdalena Bay Incident
  - Magrane, Monica
  - Magruder, General John, military mission
  - Mahan, Rear Admiral Alfred Thayer, U.S.N.
  - Mail record
  - Mail seizures
  - Mailing lists, Mr. Hornbeck
  - Malaysia
  - "Male Philosophers,", 1931
  - Malenkoff
  - Malik
  - Mallon, A. E.
  - Mallory, Walter H.
  - Mallory, Walter H., "The Open Door in China,", circa 1947
  - Man (Box 286)
  - Manchukuo
    - General
    - Government
    - Japan loan to
    - Japan Protocol
    - Postal service
    - Telegrams
    - Trade
    - Visas
  - Manchuria
    - General
    - "To 1915, Japan in China, Ten Years of"
    - 1929
    - 1931 (Box 287)
    - 1931-1932
      - American action
      - American cooperation with League
      - American notes
      - Anglo-American cooperation
      - Boycott (see also "China: Boycott")
      - Britain
      - Buell, R. L., "The World's Peace Machinery Undergoes Its Severest Test"
      - Chamberlain case
      - China
      - Chinchow
      - Far East business and trade, effect on
      - Far Eastern trade
      - General
      - Government, new
      - Japan
      - "Japan's Aim," by Rodney Gilbert
      - Japan's aim and policy
      - "Japan's Attitude toward the United States," by Hugh Byas
      - Japan, foreign investments in
      - Japan's responsibility
      - Kellogg Peace Pact (Box 288)
      - The League
      - The League and U.S. action
      - Open Door in China
      - Peace
      - Question, general comments
      - Shanghai
      - Situation, Manchurian
      - Sokolsky articles
      - The Soviet
      - Stimson's letter, February
      - Stimson-Shidehara misunderstanding
      - Tientsin
      - Treaties
      - Tsitshar
      - United States action and policy
      - Manchuria (Box 289)
      - Abend, Hallett
      - Anshan Iron Works
      - Baker, C. E., on America's interest in
      - Bean Oil Trade, 1921
      - Chinese Eastern Railway, Freeman
      - Clippings, 2.0 folders)
      - Economic development of
      - General
      - Geography of, Fenneman
      - Hanson, George C., 1930
      - Incident
      - Incident (Box 290)
      - Japan and
      - Japanese business in
      - Japanese demands, 1916
      - Japanese Railway lines, four new
      - Japanese troops in
      - Johnson, Japan in South Manchuria
      - Kinney, H. W.
      - Knox neutralization scheme
      - Kwangtung Government
      - Kwangtung Province, 1926
      - Manchoukuo
      - Manchurian and Mongolian Four Railways Loan
      - Miscellaneous
      - Pamphleted clippings
      - Pamphlets
      - Pamphlets, 2.0 folders) (Box 291)
      - Railways
      - Railways, Blakeslee
      - Railway guards
      - Situation, Hanson-Salisbury reports
      - South (Box 292)
        - Currency, 1924
        - Discriminations in, 1922
        - History of, diplomatic, since 1904
        - Japan's relations with
        - Railway, 1921
        - Railway, proposed loan
        - Railway reports, etc.
        - Rhea
      - Trade conditions, 1921
      - Trade possibilities
      - Young, C. W., appendices, treaties re Manchuria
        See also: China: Young, C. W., appendices, treaties re Manchuria
      - Mandates (Box 293)
  - Manifestoes
  - Mann, John W.
  - Man's Duties
  - Mansfield, Senator Mike
  - Mansholt, Jr. S. L.
  - Mao Tse-Tung
  - Mar, Timothy T.
  - March of Time
  - Margraten Cemetery, Holland
  - Margraten-Heuschen, Holland
  - Marietta College
  - Marina Incident
  - Marines
  - Maritime Commerce in war
  - Maritime Commission
  - Mark Twain
  - Markerink, J. H.
  - Marshall, Gen. George Catlett (Chief of Staff, U.S.A.)
  - Marshall, George, Sec. of State, letter to, 1947
  - Marshall, Hugh (Box 294)
  - Marsman, J. H.
  - Martin, Charles E.
  - Martin, Lawrence
  - Martin, Marilyn
  - Martin, William
  - Marvel, Josiah, Jr.
  - Marvin, George
  - Marvin, Matthew A.
  - Maryland University, 11th Annual Conference on Chinese-American Cultural Relations, 1965 May 7
  - Maryland University, Chinese-American Cultural Relations, 1955 May 27
  - Maryland University
    See also: China Institute
  - Mashmeyer, Veda
  - Mason, Charles W.
  - Mason, Edward S.
  - Masonic, Borgen, 1962 March 16
  - Masonic order
  - Mast, Harry E.
  - Matchan, Paloma Press
  - Mathews, William, 5.0 folders)
  - Matsudaira's project (Box 295)
  - Matthews, H. Freeman
  - Mattox, Mrs. Elmer L.
  - Maxwell, General Russell L.
  - May, Earl Chapin
  - May, Lieutenant Ernest R., 1954 March
  - Maya
  - Mayer, Ferdinand L.
  - Mayer, Richard J.
  - Mayer, Major William, memorandum on Sino-Japanese conflict
  - Maze, Sir Frederick
  - McLean, Mrs.
  - Meadows, T. T., "The Chinese....etc."
  - Meany, George
  - Mears, Eliot G.
  - Measurement, units of
  - Medals of Freedom
  - Mediation, good offices
  - Mediation
  - Medicare, applications, etc.
  - Mees, A.
  - Melby, Joyn
  - Meloney, Mrs. William Brown
  - Memoirs, S. K. Hornbeck, subjects for (Box 296)
  - Memoranda
  - Men
  - Mencken, H. L.
  - Menten, Mr. & Mrs.
  - Menus and recipes
  - Menzies, R. G.
  - "Merchant Marine," by Ralph Rushmore in the Magazine of Wall Street, 1932 May
  - Merchant vessels
  - Merica, Arnold A.
  - Merica, Paul D.
  - Merrill, Lynch
  - Merrill, Lynch, 1954 August
  - Messer, Paul
  - Messersmith, George S.
  - Metropolitan Club
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art
  - ter Meulen, Jacob
  - Mexico
  - Mexico, minister of
  - Mexico and Nicaragua
  - Mexico-U.S., relations with, C. C. Hyde and C. L. Jones
  - Meyner, J.
  - Michener, D. Roland (Box 297)
  - Michie, Allan A.
  - Michiels Van Kessenich
  - Middle East, 3.0 folders)
  - Midwest Chinese Student and Alumni Services
  - Migel, J. M.
  - Military Attache
  - Military equipment and supplies
  - Military Intelligence, British M. I. C., set up, 1943
  - Military Intelligence Division, Major Churchill on
  - Military Intelligence Division, Colonel Reeves on
  - Military Intelligence Division, Reserve
  - Military Intelligence Division Summary, 1922-1924
  - Military Intelligence Division Summany, 1925-1926 (Box 298)
  - Military Intelligence, Reserve Officers Association, 1933 February 15
  - Military missions
  - Military Order of the World Wars
    - General
    - Address, 1933 February 9
    - Pittsburgh meeting
    - To August 1962
    - Quemoy
    - On "Quemoy,", 1960 December 8
    - Resolutions, 1953-1954
  - Military Staffs
  - Millard, Thomas F. (2 folders) (Box 299)
  - Miller, Colonel
  - Miller, Douglas
  - Miller, Francis P.
  - Miller, Hunter
  - Miller, Ransford S.
  - Miller, Raymond
  - Miller, William E.
  - Millikin, Eugene D.
  - Milling, General T. Dewitt
  - Millspaugh, A. C., "The Position in Persia,", 1920
  - Minifee (and Nash), to call me
  - Minnigerode, Nancy
  - Minor, Clark H.
  - Missions, 2.0 folders)
  - Mitchell, General William (Box 300)
  - Mithun, Jacqueline S.
  - Moe, Henry Allen
  - Modern Age, David S. Collier, publisher
  - Modern internationalism, bibliography
  - Moffat, Abbot Low
  - Moffat, Pierrepont
  - Moist, Ronald F.
  - Moley, Raymond
  - de Monchy, S. J. R.
  - Money
  - Money, checks, etc.
  - Mongolia
  - Mongols
  - Monnet, Jean
  - Monroe, Paul
  - Monroe, William S.
  - Monroe Doctrine, 3.0 folders)
  - Monsoons (Box 301)
  - Montague, Lt. Gen. Percival J.
  - Montgomery, John C.
  - Montgomery, William L.
  - Moody, Col. Lucien B.
  - Moon
  - Moore, Frederick
  - Moore, J. B., "Decalogue for Diplomats"
  - Moore, R. Walton
  - Moorefield Celebration, 1963 September
  - Moorhead, Mrs. Helen Howell
  - Moral considerations
  - Moral Rearmament
  - Morale
  - Morals and morality
  - Moran, Hugh A.
  - Morgan, John H.
  - Morgan, Sidney
  - Morgenthau Diaries
  - Morgue, 2.0 folders)
  - Morley, Felix (Box 302)
  - Morley, John
  - Morris, R., I. P. R. hearings, etc.
  - Morse, Senator Wayne, on China policy, admission, etc., 1961 July
  - Morton, Sterling, 3.0 folders)
  - Moseley, General George Van Horn
  - Mosely, Prof. Philip E.
  - Moser, C. K.
  - Mosle, Alexander G. (Box 303)
  - Most Favored Nation Clause (4 folders)
  - Most Favored Nation Clause (Box 304)
    Apparently material brought from Wisconsin to Washington, probably material for the S. K. Hornbeck article on the Most Favored Nation Clause.
  - Most Favored Nation Clause, China, 1842-1844
  - Most Favored Nation Clause and Policy, Germany and
  - Mother's Day
  - Motherwell, Hiram
  - Moths
  - Mott, John R.
  - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel
  - Muccio, John J.
  - Mulder, J.
  - Mundt, Angus
  - Mundt, Senator Karl E.
  - Murch, John D.
  - Murdock, Senator Abe
  - Murphy, Frank
  - Murphy, Henry Killam
  - Murphy, Robert D.
  - Murray, Wallace
  - Myers, Denys
  - Myers, Mryl S.
  - van Naaldwijk, Burgemeester (Box 305)
  - Naeem, Abdul B.
  - Naider, Mrs. Francis S.
  - Narcotics
  - Nash, Ernest T.
  - Nash, Philip C.
  - Nash, Vernon
  - Nash, Walter
  - Nason, John
  - Nason, William F.
  - National Archives
  - National Association of Retired Civil Employees
  - National Board of Fire Underwriters
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc.
  - National Catholic Welfare Conference
  - National City Bank
  - National Council on Asian Affairs
  - National Economic and Social Planning Association
  - National Foreign Trade Council
  - National Foreign Trade Council, Convention, 1938
  - National Foreign Trade Council (2 folders), 1944-1946 (Box 306)
  - National Foreign Trade Council Convention, 1940-1942; 3.0 folders)
  - National Geographic Society
  - National Industrial Conference Board, Inc.
  - National Investors Council
  - National League of Women Voters
  - National Planning Association
  - National Policy Committee
  - National Press Club
  - National Press Club, 1965
  - National Research Council (Box 307)
  - National Review, 1966
  - National War College, Hornbeck lecture, 1949
  - National War College, 1949
  - National War College, Hornbeck lecture, 1956 December 4
  - Nationalism
  - Nationality Act of 1940
  - Naturalization laws, revision of
  - Nature
  - Naval Attache
  - Naval Bases
  - Naval Conference
  - Naval Conference, 1934-1936; 3.0 folders)
  - Naval Conference, press (Box 308)
  - Naval Intelligence
  - Naval War College
  - Navies
  - Navy, 1915-1946
  - Navy Department (Box 309)
  - Navy Department, Office of Naval Intelligence
  - Navy, in Far East
  - Navy League
  - Navy, press clippings
  - Near East
    - General
    - 1932
    - Bibliography
    - Clippings
    - King-Crane Report
    - Meiloff documents and map (Box 310)
    - Secret agreements
    - Temperley
    - Turkey, Constitution of
    - Turkey and the Greek claims
    - Turkey, Ottoman debt
    - Turkey settlement, Buckler and British government
    - Turkey, statistics, maps, diagrams
    - Turkey tariff
  - Nederland - Amerika Institut
  - Needham, Joseph
  - Needham, Leslie W.
  - Neff, Priscilla
  - Negotiations
  - Neher, L.
  - Neising (Mr.)
  - Nelson, Frederic
  - Nelson, John
  - Nelson, L. R.
  - Nepal
  - Neprud, Carl
  - Nes, David
  - Neese, Arthur
  - Nestinger, Edward
  - Netherlands
    - 1942-1948, 3.0 folders)
    - 1966 (Box 311)
    - American Foundation
    - American relations, Dutch help to America in 1776-1796
    - America University League
    - America University Week
    - Bernhard, Prince of the Netherlands
    - East Indies, 2.0 folders)
    - Economic (Box 312)
    - Embassy
    - Government
    - Government, Prime Minister
    - Information Bureau
    - Juliana, Princess of the Netherlands
    - Legation
    - Loudon, Dr. Alexander (ambassador)
    - Lumber
    - Netherlands House
    - West Indies
    - Wilhelmina, Queen of the Netherlands
    - Wilhelmina, 1961-1962
  - Nettels, Curtis P.
  - Neuhauser, R. L.
  - Neutral commerce
  - Neutral governments, conversations
  - Neutral League (Sweden, Norway, Denmark)
  - Neutral rights
  - Neutral zones
  - Neutralism
  - Neutrality
    - Neutrality and neutralism
    - 1933-1936 (Box 313)
    - 1937-1939 (Box 314)
    - 1940-1945 (Box 315)
    - Neutrality Act
    - Boundary lines
    - Miscellaneous items (3 folders), 1932-1939 (Box 316)
    - Pamphlets, 1915-1931
    - Press articles, 1936
    - Press articles, 1937-1938, 1940-1941 (Box 317)
    - Stimson, American Neutrality Policy, Council on Foreign Relations
    - U.S. Proclamations, etc.
    - Wilson on neutrality
  - Neutrality Zone, Pan American
  - Neville, Edwin
  - New Caledonia
  - New Commonwealth
  - New Frontier
  - New Guinea
  - New Hebrides
  - New Leader, The
  - New Orient Society of America
  - New Republic
  - New York Herald-Tribune
  - New York Times
  - New York University, 1949
  - New Zealand
  - New Zealand Legation
  - New Zealand and Nash
  - Newell, Isaac (Box 318)
  - News Agencies, Ivy Lee, The Press Today
  - News Bulletins and memoranda, 1945-1946
  - News, the Washington Daily
  - Newsmen
  - Newspaper comment
  - Newsweek
  - Newton, (Mr.)
  - Neymann, A.
  - Niblack, Mrs. Albert P.
  - Nichol, Frederick William
  - Nichols, Ruth
  - Nichols, Shirley
  - Nicolaes, P. J.
  - Nicolson, Harold
  - Nielson, Fred K.
  - Nieuwenhuis, O. J. Tj. N. Domela
  - Nijhoff, Wouter
  - Nijmegen
  - Niles, Judge Emory H., 1966
  - Nimitz, Chester P.
  - 1914
  - 1930's
  - 1937
  - 1938-1941
  - 1941, S. K. Hornbeck memos
  - 1941, June, July
  - 1941, memo of November 27 by S. K. Hornbeck
  - 1942
  - 1944
  - 1944, foreign policy and public opinion
  - 1945
  - 1946
  - 1947
  - 1949, Vincent Winfield's book, What Next in China?
  - 1950
  - circa 1950
  - 1965
  - circa 1970
  - Nitchie, Elizabeth
  - Nixon, Richard M.
  - No Far East (Box 319)
  - Noble, G. Bernard
  - Noble, G. Bernard, Cosmos Club
  - Noel, F. Regis
  - Noel-Baker, Philip J.
  - Non-aggression
  - Non-aggression Pact, Russia-Germany
  - Non-annexation
  - Non-belligerency
  - Non-combatants
  - Nonni River Bridge
  - Non-recognition, 3.0 folders)
  - Non-recognition, 1933, 1945
  - Non-recogition, Ethiopia
  - Nonsense
  - Noothoven van Goor-Nelson, (Mrs.) W. A.
  - Nord, F. L.
  - Norins, Martin
  - Norlin, George
  - Norman, J. V., Jr. (Box 320)
  - Norris, Howard D.
  - North Africa
  - North African situation
  - North Atlantic Coast Fisheries
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization Pact, 2.0 folders)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization Conference at Georgetown University, May 7-8, 1964
  - Nord, F. Z.
  - Norton, Henry Kittredge
    - General
    - "China as an International Problem," Naval War College, 1926
    - "China: Ten Vivid Scenes,", 1927
    - "Chinese Armies and Parties,", 1927
    - "Fever Spots in the World's Politics"
    - "Foreign Office Organization,", 1929
  - Norton, Mrs. Robert M.
  - Norton, W. W. and Company, Inc.
  - Norway
  - Norweb, R. Henry
  - Norwegian Legation
  - Notes
    - China to U.S., 1932
    - Japan to U.S., 1932 January 16
    - U.S. to Japan, 1915, 1931
    - U.S. to Japan and China, 1931-1932
    - Notter, Harley, 1943-1944 (Box 321)
  - Nover, Barnet
  - Nuclear
  - Nye, Senator
  - Oath (Box 322)
  - Oberndorff, Count
  - Obituary, Hornbeck for
  - O'Brien, Arthur
  - O'Brien, Robert L.
  - O'Bryan, Deric
  - Observers
  - O'Connell, Daniel
  - O'Conroy, Timothy
  - O'Donoghue, M. J.
  - Oettinger, Mrs. Frank
  - Offerhaus, W. A.
  - Office of Facts and Figures
  - Office of Far Eastern Affairs
  - Office of Foreign Economic Administration, Leo Crowley, Administrator
  - Office of Foreign Economic Coordination
  - Office of Political Affairs, Hornbeck
  - Office of Special Assistant, Hornbeck
  - Office of the Coordinator of Information (Box 323)
  - Office of Strategic Services
  - Office of War Information
  - Office of War Information, Press
  - Office supplies (Box 324)
  - Officer, Keith
  - Offie, Carmel
  - Ogg, Frederic A.
  - Oil
  - Oil companies
  - Oil pollution
  - Old books, Marguis D's Old Psalter
  - Old China hands
  - Old China Hands, Directory, Julean Arnold
  - Olds, Herbert V.
  - Olson, William C.
  - "One World"
  - O'Neil, Edward G.
  - Open Door
  - Opinion Convention, 1912, 1916
  - Oppenheimer
  - Orbis
  - Orchard, John E.
  - Orders
  - Organization of American States
  - Oriental Development Company, Hornbeck on
  - Oriental Rugs
  - Orientalia, Inc.
  - "Orientation," Literary Society, 1963 March
  - O'Ryan, Major General John
  - Osborne, Lithgow
  - Osmena, Sergio
  - Otterson, John E.
  - Otto, Col. L. F.
  - Oudendijk, W. J.
  - Outlook, letter to, 1915
  - Outpost
  - Overseas Chinese
  - Overseas corporation
  - Overtime reports (Box 325)
  - Oxford
  - Oxford, Castell's Catalog, 1957
  - Oxford Group
  - Oxford Society
  - Oxford University Press
  - PA/H versus FE (Box 326)
  - P.E.N. Club
  - Pacific, The
  - Pacific bases
  - Pacific cables
  - Pacific Coast, Survey of Race Relations, 1925
  - Pacific Islands
    - General
    - American possessions in Pacific, their commercial and strategic value
    - Blakeslee
    - Blakeslee, "Former German Pacific Islands"
    - Britain's Pacific Island Dominion
    - German colonial possessions surrendered since 1914
    - Hawaii
    - Macao (Box 327)
    - Pacific Ocean fortifications
    - Problems of
    - Samoa
    - U.S. possessions in the Pacific, strategic and commercial value
  - Pacific policy
  - Pacifism
  - Pacifism, Birkenhead on
  - Packer, Earl
  - Padelford, Norman J.
  - Padoux, Georges
  - Page, Charles A.
  - Page, Frank C.
  - Paige, Sidney
  - Paine, Robert Treat
  - Pakistan
  - Palen, Lewis S.
  - Palmer, Wayne Francis
  - Pan, Stephen
  - Pan American Airways, Incorporated
  - Pan American Union
  - Pan Pacific Conference, 1922
  - Pan Pacific Union
  - Panama
  - Panama Canal Zone
  - Pannell, Mrs.
  - Pardridge, William
  - Paris Peace Conference
    - General
    - Adriatic, Wilson's note (Box 328)
    - American Commission, composition and functions
    - American Commission, telephone directory
    - American summary of Peace Treaty
    - Arnold, program
    - Austrian Treaty, China's interest
    - Bibliography
    - China boycott, instructions to Peking
    - China and Japan, Manchester Guardian
    - China, official program
    - China, Peace Commissioners
    - China, question of signing treaty
    - China's reply to Japan
    - China's statement to press, 1919 May 6
    - China in the Treaty
    - China Treaty clauses, our proposals
    - China, Williams - Hornbeck memo
    - Chinese claim, precis of document based on Koos presentation
    - Chinese Delegation
    - Chinese Delegation Protest
    - Chinese Delegation, refusal to sign the German treaty, explanation, June 28
    - Chinese dispatches
    - China, German and Australian interests
    - Chinese petitions
    - Chinese press reception
    - Chinese proposals, early
    - China, miscellaneous
    - Chinda, Viscount, "Complete Understanding," China and Japan
    - Chinda, Viscount, on China and Japan
    - Department questions, outstanding (Box 329)
    - Experts memo, order for
    - Extraterritoriality
    - Far East problems and recommendations
    - Far East recommendations (fragments)
    - Far East Supplement
    - Finch
    - Gallagher, P.
    - Hornbeck at Peace Conference
    - Institute of International Affairs
    - Italian claims re Tientsin Concession
    - Japan at the Conference
    - Japanese controversy, Sino-
    - Japanese demands at Peking, 1919 February
    - Korean Delegation
    - Korea, official claims
    - Korea at Peace Conference
    - Korean representations
    - Kurd claims
    - La Baionnette cartoon, Paris, 1919 July 14
    - Lansing, R., sketches, 1919 May